rockethub.com 2018-06-25

# Introduction

Introduction
Welcome to the ELEQT Group Limited privacy notice.
ELEQT Group respects your privacy and is committed to protecting your personal data. This privacy notice
will inform you as to how we look after your personal data and tell you about your privacy rights and how
the law protects to you. This is the updated Privacy Notice for ELEQT Group’s websites; www.eleqt.com
and www.rockethub.com, referred to as ‘The Websites’ or ‘Our Websites’.
This privacy notice is provided in a layered format so you can click through to the specific areas set out
below. Please also use the Glossary to understand the meaning of some of the terms used in this privacy
notice.
     1. Important Information and Who We Are
     2. The Data We Collect About You
     3. How Is Your Personal Data Collected
     4. How We Use Your Personal Data
     5. Disclosures of Your Personal Data
     6. International Transfers
     7. Data Security
     8. Data Retention
     9. Your Legal Rights
     10. Glossary
     1. IMPORTANT INFORMATION AND WHO WE ARE
          Purpose of this privacy notice
          This privacy notice aims to give you information on how ELEQT Group collects and processes
          your personal data through your use of this website or our services, including any data you may
          provide through this website when you sign up to our newsletter, purchase a product or service
          or take part in a competition. These websites iare not intended for children.
          It is important that you read this privacy notice together with any other privacy notice or fair
          processing notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing
          personal data about you so that you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This
          privacy notice supplements the other notices and is not intended to override them.
          Controller
          The ELEQT Group is made up of different legal entities. This privacy notice is issued on behalf of
          each member of the ELEQT Groups so when we mention " ELEQT Group ", "we", "us" or "our" in
          this privacy notice, we are referring to the relevant company in the ELEQT Group responsible for
          processing your data. ELEQT Group (UK) Limited is the controller and responsible for the
          websites.

   We have appointed a data protection officer (DPO) who is responsible for overseeing questions
   in relation to this privacy notice. If you have any questions about this privacy notice, including
   any requests to exercise your legal rights, please contact the DPO using the details set out below.
   Contact details
         o   Full name of legal entity: ELEQT Group (UK) Limited
         o   Name or title of DPO: Ronald de la Fuente
         o   Email address: Ronald.delafuente@ELEQTGroup.com
         o   Postal address: 142 Cromwell Road, London, SW7 4EF, United Kingdom
         o   Telephone number: +1 (646) 652-6886
   You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner's Office
   (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues (www.ico.org.uk). We would,
   however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so
   please contact us in the first instance.
   Changes to the privacy notice and your duty to inform us of changes
   This version was last updated on 10 May 2018.
   It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us
   informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.
   Third-party links
   These websites may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on
   those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about
   you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy
   statements. When you leave our websites, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every
   website you visit.
2. HOW IS YOUR PERSONAL DATA COLLECTED?
   We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:
         o   Direct interactions. You may give us your Identity, Contact and Financial Data by filling
             in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes
             personal data you provide when you join the ELEQT Group Membership Club or place a
             request for services with ELEQT Group and includes circumstances in which you:
                  ▪   apply for our products or services;
                  ▪   create an account on our websites;
                  ▪   subscribe to our service or publications;
                  ▪   request marketing to be sent to you;
                  ▪   enter a competition, promotion or survey; or
                  ▪   give us some feedback.
         o   Automated technologies or interactions. As you interact with our websites, we may
             automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and
             patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies, server logs and other similar
             technologies. We may also receive Technical Data about you if you visit other websites
             employing our cookies. Please see our cookie policy for further details.
         o   Third parties or publicly available sources. We may receive personal data about you
             from various third parties and public sources as set out below:

                  ▪   Technical Data from analytics providers such as Google based outside the EU.
                  ▪   Identity and Contact Data from publicly availably sources such as Companies
                      House and the Electoral Register based inside the EU.
3. THE DATA WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU
   Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which
   that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed
   (anonymous data).
   We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you which we
   have grouped together follows:
        o    Identity Data includes first name, maiden name, last name, username or similar
             identifier, marital status, title, date of birth and gender.
        o    Contact Data includes billing address, delivery address, email address and telephone
             numbers.
        o    Marketing and Communications Data includes your preferences in receiving marketing
             from us and our third parties and your communication preferences
        o    Financial Data includes bank account and payment card details.
        o    Transaction Data includes details about payments to and from you and other details of
             products and services you have purchased from us.
        o    Technical Data includes internet protocol (IP) address, your login data, browser type and
             version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating
             system and platform and other technology on the devices you use to interact with or
             access these websites.
        o    Profile Data includes your membership identification number, purchases or orders made
             by you, your interests, preferences, feedback and survey responses.
        o    Usage Data includes information about how you use our websites, products and
             services.
   We also collect, use and share Aggregated Data such as statistical or demographic data for any
   purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered
   personal data in law as this data does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example,
   we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific
   website feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so
   that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which
   will be used in accordance with this privacy notice.
   We may collect any Special Categories of Personal Data about you (this includes details about
   your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political
   opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric
   data).
   We do not collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.
   If you fail to provide personal data
   Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with
   you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the
   contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with goods or
   services). In this case, we may have to cancel a product or service you have with us but we will
   notify you if this is the case at the time.
4. HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL DATA

    We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your
    personal data in the following circumstances:
1. Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with
    you
2. Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests
    and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
3. Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.
    Generally we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data other than
    in relation to sending third party direct marketing communications to you via email or text
    message. You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by contacting us.
    Purposes for which we will use your personal data
    We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your
    personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our
    legitimate interests are where appropriate.
    Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the
    specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us if you need details about the
    specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one
    ground has been set out in the table below.
    Purpose/Activity                  Type of data         Lawful basis/bases for processing including basis of
                                                           legitimate interest
    To register you as a new      4.  (a) Identity         Performance of a contract with you
    member or customer            5.  (b) Contact
    To process and deliver your 9. (a) Identity        14. (a) Performance of a contract with you
    requests and orders including:10. (b) Contact      15. (b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to recover
                                  11. (c) Financial        debts due to us)
6.  (a) Fulfilment of requests placed
    by you or on your behalf      12. (d) Transaction
7.  (b) Manage payments, fees and 13. (e) Marketing and
    charges                           Communications
8.  (c) Collect and recover money
    owed to us
    To manage our relationship with
                                  18. (a) Identity     22. (a) Performance of a contract with you
    you which will include:       19. (b) Contact      23. (b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation
                                  20. (c) Profile      24. (c) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our
16. (a) Notifying you about changes
                                                           records updated and to study how customers use our
    to our terms or privacy policy21. (d) Marketing and
                                      Communications       products/services)
17. (b) Asking you to leave a review
    or take a survey
    To enable you to partake in a25. (a) Identity      30. (a) Performance of a contract with you
    prize draw, competition or 26. (b) Contact         31. (b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study
    complete a survey                                      how customers use our products/services, to develop
                                  27. (c) Profile
                                                           them and grow our business)
                                  28. (d) Usage
                                  29. (e) Marketing and
                                      Communications
    To administer and protect our32. (a) Identity      35. (a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running
    business and these websites 33. (b) Contact            our business, provision of administration and IT
    (including troubleshooting, data                       services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the

analysis, testing, system    34. c) Technical         context of a business reorganisation or group
maintenance, support, reporting                       restructuring exercise)
and hosting of data)                              36. (b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation
To deliver relevant website 37.   (a) Identity        Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how
content and advertisements to38.  (b) Contact         customers use our products/services, to develop them,
you and measure or understand                         to grow our business and to inform our marketing
the effectiveness of the     39.  (c) Profile         strategy)
advertising we serve to you 40.   (d) Usage
                             41. (e) Marketing and
                                  Communications
                             42. (f) Technical
To use data analytics to improve
                             43.  (a) Technical       Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types
our websites, products/services,
                             44.  (b) Usage           of customers for our products and services, to keep
marketing, customer                                   our websites updated and relevant, to develop our
relationships and experiences                         business and to inform our marketing strategy)
To make suggestions and      45.  (a) Identity        Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our
recommendations to you about 46.  (b) Contact         products/services and grow our business)
goods or services that may be of
interest to you              47.  (c) Technical
                             48.  (d) Usage
                             49. (e) Profile
Marketing
We strive to provide you with choices regarding certain personal data uses, particularly around
marketing and advertising:
Promotional offers from us
We may use your Identity, Contact, Technical, Usage and Profile Data to form a view on what we
think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which
products, services and offers may be relevant for you (we call this marketing).
You will receive marketing communications from us if you have requested information from us
or placed a request with us or purchased goods or services from us or if you provided us with
your details when you entered a competition or registered for a promotion and, in each case,
you have not opted out of receiving that marketing.
Third-party marketing
We will get your express opt-in consent before we share your personal data with any company
outside the ELEQT Group of companies for marketing purposes.
Opting out
You can ask us or third parties to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by contacting
us at any time.
Where you opt out of receiving these marketing messages, this will not apply to personal data
provided to us as a result of a product/service purchase, product/service experience or other
transactions.
Change of purpose
We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we
reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with
the original purpose. If you wish to get an explanation as to how the processing for the new
purpose is compatible with the original purpose, please contact us.
If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will
explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.

   Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in
   compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.
5. DISCLOSURES OF YOUR PERSONAL DATA
   We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out
   in the table in paragraph 4 above.
o  Internal Third Parties as set out in the Glossary.
o  External Third Parties as set out in the Glossary.
o  Specific third parties such as ELEQT Groupfranchise partners.
o  Third parties to whom we may choose to sell, transfer, or merge parts of our business or our
   assets. Alternatively, we may seek to acquire other businesses or merge with them. If a change
   happens to our business, then the new owners may use your personal data in the same way as
   set out in this privacy notice.
   We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in
   accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal
   data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified
   purposes and in accordance with our instructions.
6. INTERNATIONAL TRANSFERS
   We share your personal data within the ELEQT Group Group. This will involve transferring your
   data outside the European Economic Area (EEA).
   Many of our external third parties are based outside the European Economic Area (EEA) so their
   processing of your personal data will involve a transfer of data outside the EEA.
   Whenever we transfer your personal data out of the EEA, we ensure a similar degree of
   protection is afforded to it by ensuring at least one of the following safeguards is implemented:
o  We will only transfer your personal data to countries that have been deemed to provide an
   adequate level of protection for personal data by the European Commission.
o  Where we use certain service providers, we may use specific contracts approved by the
   European Commission which give personal data the same protection it has in Europe.
o  Where we use providers based in the US, we may transfer data to them if they are part of the
   Privacy Shield which requires them to provide similar protection to personal data shared
   between the Europe and the US. For further details, see European Commission: EU-US Privacy
   Shield.
   Please contact us if you want further information on the specific mechanism used by us when
   transferring your personal data out of the EEA.
7. DATA SECURITY
   We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being
   accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we
   limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third
   parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our
   instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.
   We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify
   you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.
8. DATA RETENTION
   How long will you use my personal data for?
   We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected
   it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.

    To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount,
    nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or
    disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and
    whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal
    requirements.
    By law we have to keep basic information about our customers (including Contact, Identity,
    Financial and Transaction Data) for six years after they cease being customers for tax purposes.
    In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see Request erasure below for further
    information.
    In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be
    associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this
    information indefinitely without further notice to you.
9. YOUR LEGAL RIGHTS
    Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your
    personal data. To find out more about these rights, please refer to paragraph 10 below:
o   Request access to your personal data.
o   Request correction of your personal data.
o   Request erasure of your personal data.
o   Object to processing of your personal data.
o   Request restriction of processing your personal data.
o   Request transfer of your personal data.
o   Right to withdraw consent.
    If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us.
    No fee usually required
    You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other
    rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive
    or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.
    What we may need from you
    We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and
    ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a
    security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to
    receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request
    to speed up our response.
    Time limit to respond
    We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it may take us longer
    than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In
    this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.
10. GLOSSARY
    Lawful Basis
    Legitimate Interest means the interest of our business in conducting and managing our business
    to enable us to give you the best service/product and the best and most secure experience. We
    make sure we consider and balance any potential impact on you (both positive and negative) and
    your rights before we process your personal data for our legitimate interests. We do not use
    your personal data for activities where our interests are overridden by the impact on you (unless
    we have your consent or are otherwise required or permitted to by law). You can obtain further
    information about how we assess our legitimate interests against any potential impact on you in
    respect of specific activities by contacting us

  Performance of Contract means processing your data where it is necessary for the performance
  of a contract to which you are a party or to take steps at your request before entering into such a
  contract.
  Comply with a legal or regulatory obligation means processing your personal data where it is
  necessary for compliance with a legal or regulatory obligation that we are subject to.
  Third Parties
  Internal Third Parties
  Other companies in the ELEQT Groupacting as joint controllers or processors and who are based
  in the United States of America, the United Arab Emirates and Hong Kong and provide:
o services pursuant to the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
o IT and system administration services and undertake leadership reporting.
  External Third Parties
o Franchise partners acting as joint controllers or processors who may provide services pursuant to
  the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
o Service providers acting as processors based who provide IT and system administration services.
o Professional advisers acting as processors or joint controllers including lawyers, bankers, auditors
  and insurers who provide consultancy, banking, legal, insurance and accounting services.
o HM Revenue & Customs, regulators and other authorities acting as processors or joint
  controllers based in the United Kingdom who require reporting of processing activities in certain
  circumstances.
  Your Legal Rights
  You have the right to:
  Request access to your personal data (commonly known as a "data subject access request"). This
  enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are
  lawfully processing it.
  Request correction of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any
  incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the
  accuracy of the new data you provide to us.
  Request erasure of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal
  data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask
  us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to
  object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or
  where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that
  we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons
  which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.
  Object to processing of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or
  those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you
  want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights
  and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for
  direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling
  legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.

Request restriction of processing of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend
the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios: (a) if you want us to establish the
data's accuracy; (b) where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it; (c)
where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish,
exercise or defend legal claims; or (d) you have objected to our use of your data but we need to
verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.
Request the transfer of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a
third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-
readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially
provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with
you.
Withdraw consent at any time where we are relying on consent to process your personal data.
However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw
your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or
services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.
